<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aleph-Zero-Heros on Aleph-Zero-Heroes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aleph-Zero-Heros on Aleph-Zero-Heroes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia (Part II): Data Structures for Data Science</title>
      <link>/posts/post_julia2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post_julia2/</guid>
      <description>Intro I mentioned in my last post on Julia that dictionaries are incredibly useful data structures for data science. I thought that warranted a little more discussion. And it leads to another data structure that we use a lot: Data Frames. They&amp;rsquo;re the topic for today.
Dictionaries A dictionary (in computer programming) is much like an English dictionary. It takes a set of objects (the keys) and maps them to something else (the values).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MCU Timeline Part I</title>
      <link>/posts/post_mcu_timeline1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post_mcu_timeline1/</guid>
      <description>I talked about the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) and why it&amp;rsquo;s interesting in a previous post. Have a read if you want to get started on this. Today I want to talk about a way of visualising the relationships between the characters and the movies in a timeline (shown above).
And as a minor note, I just saw Captain Marvel, which is brilliant, but required a few last minute alterations to the timeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Julia (Part I): Web APIs</title>
      <link>/posts/post_julia1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post_julia1/</guid>
      <description>Julia for Data Science Data science has a major component that is computational. You can&amp;rsquo;t do very much with just a pen and paper. Luckily there are some great programming languages available. The best known these days is Python I guess, with R a close runner up (it&amp;rsquo;s a favourite of the stats community). There are a dozen others.
The up-and-coming new kid on the block is Julia. She doesn&amp;rsquo;t have as much history.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coolness of the MCU</title>
      <link>/posts/post_mcu1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/post_mcu1/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is a blog about data science and superheroes. I think there is some serious data science hidden in the pages of comics, and that&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re here to discuss.
I also think math and stats are the under-represented underpinnings of good data science. Drew Conway&amp;rsquo;s data-science Venn diagram expresses that best I think.
  Hacking and domain knowledge without mathematics is Drew&amp;rsquo;s Danger Zone.
I&amp;rsquo;ve read and watched superhero comics and movies for years, so I have just a little domain expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/posts/description/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/description/</guid>
      <description>Aleph-Zero-Heroes The title of the blog comes from a, perhaps obscure, piece of mathematics. Mathematically speaking aleph zero &amp;ndash; which we write \(\displaystyle \aleph_0\) &amp;ndash; is the cardinality of the set of natural numbers, which is a pretty mathsy way of saying &amp;ldquo;infinity&amp;rdquo;. So the name, aleph-zero-heroes, loosely translates as infinite heroes.
I don&amp;rsquo;t just care about superheroes &amp;ndash; more broadly they are a archetype that comes up frequently in the context of hybrid narratives, and that is what I want to tap into.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>